Akshay **Kalyan**



Auckland, New Zealand



+64 27 727 6866



akshaykalyan@outlook.com



github.com/xShay



Objective

Software Engineer in Development

Profile

Currently I am an undergraduate student at the University of Auckland, undertaking a Bachelor of Engineering specialising in Software Engineering. My passion in technology has placed me in the position I am in today, pursuing the rapidly growing field of Computer Science and Software. I look forward to contributing to the industry and aid in the evolution of our day to day life.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Honors), Software Engineering The University of Auckland 2012 – 2016 [expected]

CGPA: **8.7** / 9.0.

National Certificate of Educational Achievement (NCEA)

2009 – 2011

Otumoetai College Level 3 with Excellence.

Awards and Certificates

Dean's Honours List

2013

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Software Engineering students in the academic year.

Dean's Honours List

2012

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Engineering students in the academic year.

First in Class Award

University of Auckland

ENGGEN 131: Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development.

Recent Projects

Pebble Watchface: Trace

Personal Project

Technologies: C Language, Javascript, jQuery Mobile, Pebble SDK 2.0.

- Designed and created a minimalist watchface for the Pebble smartwatch, deployed via the Appstore.
- Over 1,000 unique users of the application.

Android Application: Contacts Now

University Project – Individual

Technologies: Java, SQLite, Android SDK.

- Designed and constructed a contact management application from scratch over a 6 week period.
- Implemented direct manipulation of contact data to call, send SMS, get directions and more.

Employment

Sapphire Solutions Limited

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Intern

- Redesigned, constructed, and deployed the company's website using modern HTML5 and CSS3 standards.
- Increased web presence in competitive online search by applying Search Engine Optimisation (SEO).
- Created software tools in C# for internal and external use to assist the operations of the business.
- Prepared client computers for off-site installation.

Target Road Tyres

Jan 2012 – Feb 2013

Administrator / Developer

- Involved in creating a 10 page website to allow the company to showcase thier products and services.
- Implemented standard Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) techniques.
- Tasked with administrative responsibilities including managing stock and providing tailored solutions for customers.

Volunteer Work

Peer Support Programme

2011

Student Mentor

- Participated in one-on-one interaction with first year college students to provide mentorship.
- Helped peers adjust to college life by listening to and rectifying any academic or social issues they were experiencing.

Skills

Languages

Java

C#

C++

C

Python

Internet Technologies

HTML5 & CSS3 Javascript

Mobile Development

Android

Systems

Windows XP, 7, 8 Mac OS X 10.9

Linux

Academic Transcript

Available on Request